centrelink.gov.au 2005-06-14

# Legal - Privacy & Security Statement

home | search | about us | contact us | working at centrelink | online services | overseas | we speak your language | indigenous australians | news room | publications | forms | individuals | community groups | businesses | what's new

LEGAL INFO: Disclaimer | Privacy & Security Statement | Copyright | Linking To Our Website | Your Rights | Reviews and Appeals | Privacy and Your Personal Information | Freedom of Information

Centrelink places great emphasis on maintaining and enhancing the privacy and security of your personal information. With a number of strong security measures in place and the continued development of our internet services, our main focus is on improving existing measures as well as keeping you informed about the latest developments.

## Privacy Statement:

  * Collection of information
  * When you send a message to Centrelink
  * When using online services
  * Access to information
  * Use and disclosure of information
  * Cookies

## Security Statement

  * Security Statement

* * *

## Privacy Statement:

### Collection of information

Centrelink collects a range of information about visits to the Centrelink website. The following information is stored for twelve months:

  * entry and exit pages
  * how often the site was used
  * the time of day the site was accessed
  * the length of time spent on the site
  * how much information was downloaded
  * if the visit is from a company or an individual
  * if you are browsing from Australia or overseas
  * what browser types are being used.

This information is collected for statistical analysis use only and no attempt is made by Centrelink to identify the user or their browsing activities.

#### When you send a message to Centrelink

You may provide personally identifiable information such as your name, physical address and email address, when you send us a message. Personal information collected by Centrelink is protected by the Privacy Act 1988 and the relevant confidentiality provisions contained in legislation administered by Centrelink.

### When using online services

Please refer to the Privacy Notice for each online service for details.

### Access to information

In the unlikely event of an investigation, a law enforcement agency or other government agency may exercise its legal authority to inspect our Internet Service Provider's logs.

### Use and disclosure of information

Personal information provided to Centrelink when you send us a message will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it. Your details will not be added to a general mailing list. Unless required by law, Centrelink will not disclose this information without your consent.

### Cookies

Cookies are pieces of information a website can transfer to an individual's computer hard drive. The information remains on your computer until you end your browser session or close down your computer.

Most internet browsers are preset to accept cookies, but you can choose if and how a cookie will be accepted by configuring the preferences and options in your browser.

We make no attempt to identify you in any way when you are in the public section of the Centrelink website. If you use the secure section of our website (for example our online services) we may then use cookies to:

  * determine whether your computer has support for cookies turned on (this allows us to advise that you need to enable cookies to use a particular service)
  * help identify you during your secure session
  * time your session so you will be logged off if you are not using the service for a specified time period
  * maintain an audit trail of your secure session.

For more detailed information about privacy in general please refer to Privacy & Your Personal Information or ask Centrelink for a copy of the factsheet "Your Right to Privacy".

## Security Statement

Your personal information is protected by law. These laws prohibit any person from accessing, using or disclosing any personal information in the possession of Centrelink unless it is in the performance of their duties or is in accordance with these laws. Penalties apply to those who fail to observe these provisions.

Centrelink encrypts all messages between the browser running on your PC and Centrelink's computers when these messages are sent from the Secure Messages section of the website.

The encryption process used by Centrelink is Secure Socket Layer (SSL). For SSL encryption to work, your browser must support SSL. Freely available browsers that support SSL include Netscape version 6.0 or later, Firefox version 1.0 or later and Microsoft Internet Explorer Version 4.0 or later. Go to our Downloads section of the site to get the latest version of these browsers.

While Centrelink endeavours to provide a secure internet environment, users should note that there are inherent risks associated with transmission of information via the internet. Centrelink provides alternative ways to obtain and provide information for those who do not wish to use public networks such as the internet. These include direct contact at a Customer Service Centre, telephone, facsimile or post. In some circumstances, the Centrelink security guidelines may also require us to send particular information by non-electronic means.

_Note:_ Any link to an external site is provided for your information and convenience only. Centrelink does not endorse, monitor or control such sites (or any associated organisation, product or service) and is not responsible for their content, or your access or use of them. Without limiting the forgoing, you are advised to review their privacy and security statements and take precautions to ensure any content is accurate and downloaded software is safe.

## Further information?

If you have any privacy or security concerns please visit your nearest Centrelink Customer Service Centre for advice.

**Hint:** Did you find what you were looking for? You can also try the A-Z list, quick links, search, site help or send us [feedback](https://secure.centrelink.gov.au/sims/sims_main.cfm) on how to make this a better website.

[ return to top ]

search | site help | [feedback](https://secure.centrelink.gov.au/sims/sims_main.cfm) |  A-Z | quick links | disclaimer | privacy & security | copyright | your rights | accessibility

Today's Date:  14/06/2005 - Last Modified:  25/10/2004  
URL:  http://www.centrelink.gov.au/internet/internet.nsf/legal/privacy.htm  
Centrelink ABN: 29468422437
